Mackenzie Miller

Mackmiller19@gmail.com (407) 462-7858 https://github.com/Mackmiller

TECHNOLOGIES

Languages: JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL, MQL, Swift, Arcade

Frameworks/Libraries: React.js, Node.js, Django, d3.js, Express, EJS, Axios, Request

Software: Github, Postgres, MongoDB, Heroku, ArcGIS Pro, Xcode, Unity, Adobe Suite, Maya **Concepts:** RESTful APIs, Agile, Object Oriented Programming, MVC Pattern, CRUD Operations

AWARDS/PROJECTS

Meme Cryptocurrencies: A full stack web application based upon the CoinMarketCap API which enables users to interact with coin and token information from the Meme cryptocurrency category. Built with MongoDB, Express, React and Node Music Time Machine: A full stack web application based upon the Spotify API which enables users to experience specific years in music history by filtering for music genre and release year. Built with Postgres, Express and Node

COVID-19 Dashboard: Online dashboard which allows the user to interact with Spring 2020 state-level executive orders data, built with ArcGIS and Arcade

George V. Voinovich Public Innovation Challenge: Contributed to 2020 winning team by designing dashboard prototypes ACCelerate Creativity and Innovation Festival: Designed an immersive audio experience for exhibition at Smithsonian UMiami Interactive Media Competition: Won first prize in campus-wide Physical Computing competition

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Fellow, General Assembly - 2021

Orlando, FL

- Coded web application frontends in Javascript, HTML and CSS, utilizing Node.js, Express and React
- Coded web application backends in Javascript and Python, utilizing SQL and noSQL databases
- Developed, coordinated and presented web applications in a remote-setting
- Leveraged Agile and SCRUM methodologies to deliver net new web applications
- Led a team of four software engineers to successfully release MERN stack web application on time by managing user stories, stakeholder requirements and delivery timelines

Data Visualization Designer, mackmiller.design - 2019-2021

Orlando, FL

- Created digital graphics, maps, and dashboards which improved data insight experience for users
- Contracted for businesses based in US, Europe, and Africa

Fine Arts Coordinator, Westminster Christian School - 2017-2021

Miami, FL

- Led market research and implementation of enterprise software across three school campuses
- Managed the Fine Arts department of a K-12 school and taught students ages 8 through 18

Graduate Research Assistant, University of Miami - 2018-2020

Coral Gables, FL

• Leveraged Matlab to generate data models and conducted research for computer science topics

EDUCATION

General Assembly - 2021-present

Orlando, FL

• 480+ hours of full stack development coursework

University of Miami - 2014-2020

Coral Gables, FL

- Master of Fine Arts, with emphasis in Data Visualization and User Experience (UX) Design
- Bachelor of Music, with minors in Communication and Psychology

COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT

Volunteer, Websites for Musicians - 2018-present

Orlando, FL

Assisting professional musicians with pricing and design of CMS-based websites

Volunteer Teaching Assistant, University of Miami Frost School of Music - 2014-2018

Coral Gables, FL

• Taught adults in group and individual classroom settings